sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
the "impulses" that makes you want to meet it
aitaku naru no shoudou
the "innocence" that makes you want to cry
nakitaku naru no junjou
they've gone into the summer fire
natsu no hi ni tobikonda
the fireflies aren't coming back
hotaru wa kaeranai
you didn't say a single word and left a kiss for me behind
anata wa nanimo iwazu kuchizuke wo nokoshite
and nodded as you still got burned
kitsuzuku mama unazuita ne
it was so sad that my life was wavering
kanashii hodo inochi yurameiteita
sha la la some day in the future
sha la la itsuka kitto
I will for sure hold it in my hand
boku wa te ni suru nda
it will softly set ablaze
hakanaki mune ni sotto
a light in my empty heart
hikari moeteyuke
sha la la my sweet lovely dear
sha la la itoshiki hito
I can also see you right now
anata mo mieteiru no
the dazzling moon will softly
mabayui tsuki ga sotto
illuminate the morning day
ashita wo terashite
and strongly and strongly shine on
tsuyoku tsuyoku kagayaite
A Place to Return to
(いの)いっ…。
Oww!
(サクラ)我慢して。
これで 少し楽になるはず。
Try to bear with it.
This should ease the pain a bit.
(いの)サンキュー サクラ。
Thank you, Sakura...
《サクラ : 傷が深い…
ここでは応急処置だけね》
The wound is deep.
I'll do what I can here...
(ナルト)サクラちゃん。
Sakura-chan...
幽鬼丸の様子は？
今 シズネ先輩たちが診てるわ。
How is Yuukimaru doing?
Shizune-senpai and the others
are tending to him now.
(ヒナタ)ひどい… 経絡系が…。
This is terrible. His Chakra Network is...
(シズネ)ええ
かなりのダメージを受けているわ。
Yes, he's suffered a lot of damage...
(シズネ)たとえ治療をしても 完全に
元に戻すことは不可能でしょう。
Even with treatment,
it'd be impossible to restore him
to normal completely.
三尾をコントロールする能力は
幽鬼丸の体に➡
It seems the power to control
the Three-Tails took quite a toll
かなりの負担を
強いるものだったようです。
on Yuukimaru's body.
(カカシ)命を削る術だったと？
The Jutsu reduced his life...?
はい。 精密な検査をするまでは
断定できませんが➡
Yes.
I can't be certain until we conduct
a thorough examination,
おそらく もう幽鬼丸に
以前の力は残っていないでしょう。
but it's likely that Yuukimaru no longer
has the powers he once had.
(ヤマト)これで 三尾を操る術は
失われてしまいましたね。
We've now lost our only chance
of controlling the Three-Tails...
(カカシ)この子にとっては それで
よかったのかもしれないな。
Perhaps, for this child,
it's better that way...
シズネのねえちゃん。 幽鬼丸は？
Shizune onee-chan, how is Yuukimaru?
命に別状はないわ。
まだ眠ってるけど…。
He'll live. He's still asleep...
よかったわね 助かって。
Thank goodness he made it.
ああ…。
Yeah...
だけど オレ 結局 コイツに何も
してやれなかった。
えっ。
But...
I wasn't able to help him
at all in the end...
What?
思っているヤツがいるところが
帰る場所って➡
I foolishly told him "wherever someone
thinks about you is the place to return to..."
そう偉そうに教えたのによ。
コイツは やっと見つけた帰る場所を
目の前で なくしちまったんだ。
But right before his eyes,
he lost that very place to return to.
そんなの アンタのせいじゃない。
けどよ…。
That wasn't your fault.
But still...
((幽鬼丸 : やっぱり
紅蓮さんのいるところが➡
You are the one I should return to,
after all...
ボクの帰るべき場所だもん。
紅蓮さんも ボクのいるところに
帰ってくればいいんだよ。
And I'm the one
you should return to, Guren-san.
(紅蓮)ああ… 誓う。
I promise you...
I will never leave your side.
もう お前のそばから
離れることはない。
お前のことを ずっと思い続ける。
I will always think of you.
うん。 ボクは ず～っと
紅蓮さんのことを➡
Uh-huh...
And I will always think of you, Guren-san.
思い続けているよ。
(これからも ず～っと))
From now, and forever...
うっ…。
ナルト…。
Naruto...
ごめんな 幽鬼丸。
I'm sorry. Yuukimaru...
(カツユ)状況は以上です。 綱手様。
And that is the situation, Tsunade-sama.
(綱手)そうか… わかった。
I see... I understand.
(綱手)カツユ みんなに
帰還命令を伝えろ。
Katsuyu, order everyone to return.
あっ… よろしいのですか？
Are you sure?
(綱手)仕方あるまい。
We have no choice.
このまま任務を続行させるのは
不可能だろう。
It would be impossible to
have them continue their mission.
その子供が能力を失った以上➡
Now that the child has lost his powers,
大蛇丸は もはや尾獣には
手は出せないはず。
Orochimaru can no longer
do anything to the Tailed Beast.
こちらも一度 引きあげ
体勢を整えたうえで➡
We'll pull back for now, regroup,
and come up with a new plan.
再度 作戦を立て直す。
(カツユ)しかし 三尾を狙う者は
大蛇丸だけでは…。
But Orochimaru is not the only one
who is after the Three-Tails...
そんなことは 百も承知だ。
I'm perfectly aware of that.
だが三尾は 我々を
ここまで手こずらせた相手。
But the Three-Tails is an adversary
that has given us
a great deal of trouble up to this point.
暁とて たやすくは…。
Even the Akatsuki won't
have an easy time.
すぐに交代の忍を向かわせる。
I'll send Ninja to
replace them immediately.
その者たちが到着次第
全員 撤収しろと伝えろ！
Once they arrive,
have them tell everyone to withdraw!
はい！
Right away.
綱手様のお言葉は 以上です。
Those are Tsunade-sama's orders.
わかりました。
さっそく 皆に伝えます。
Understood.
We'll inform everyone immediately.
(カカシ)火影様より新たな指示だ。
We have new orders from Hokage-sama.
我々は 現在の任務を中断。
We will abort our current mission.
すぐに
里に戻るように とのことだ。
Our orders are to return to
the village immediately.
(みんな)えっ!?
(サイ)急な話ですね。
- What?
- Huh?!
That was sudden.
(キバ)おいおい！
三尾をほっといてもいいのかよ！
Hey c'mon, is it okay to leave
the Three-Tails?
それなら心配はない。
We won't have to worry about that.
ボクたちの代わりに
監視にあたる忍が➡
They're sending Ninja to replace us
and maintain the watch.
到着することになっている。
だけど…。
But still...!
ここに残っても 今の私たちに
打てる手はないわ。
There's nothing we can do
even if we remain here.
みんな あまりに傷つきすぎた。
Everyone has suffered too many wounds.
それよりは
今回得た情報を持ち帰り➡
Tsunade-sama has decided that
it would be more effective
次の作戦に
役立てることこそ重要だと➡
if we brought back the information
we've gained this time around
綱手様は 判断されたのよ。
and apply it to our next plan instead.
出発は 明朝だ。
We'll move out tomorrow morning.
各自 移動に備え
今夜は しっかりと➡
I want you all to get a good night's rest
before we move out.
休んでおくように。
うっ… うぅ うっ…。
(牛頭)紅蓮さん…。
Guren-san...
紅蓮さん…。
牛頭 なぜ…。
Gozu?
Why're you...
なぜ お前は私を助ける？
Why're you saving me...?
覚えてますか？
あの日のことを。
Do you remember... that day?
大蛇丸の実験後 大暴れして
独房に入れられたオレは➡
I was placed in solitary after losing control
during Orochimaru's experiment...
食事はおろか
水もろくに与えてもらえず➡
I was hardly given any water
or food to speak of.
渇き果て 死にかけていた。
I was on the verge of dying from thirst.
そこへ あなたが➡
Then you came and kindly gave me
a ladleful of water.
杓にひとすくいの水を
恵んでくだすった。
それで オレは
死なずにすんだのです。
Because of that, I was able to survive.
その日以来 オレは…。
Ever since that day, I...
フン 忘れたよ
きっと気まぐれだ。
I don't even remember.
I must've been feeling generous.
たとえ そうだとしても➡
Even if that were so,
I've always admired you since then...
ずっと
お慕い申し上げております。
はっ！
紅蓮さん…。
Guren-san...
イテッ！ イタタ…。
O-Ow...
Huh?!
幽鬼丸？
Yuukimaru?!
クソッ！
Damn!
先輩。
Senpai.
ハァ ハァ… ハァ ハァ…。
クソ！ どこ
行っちまったんだってばよ。
Damn! Where could he have gone?!
アイツ まだ 体だって
まともじゃねえだろうに！
His body's...
in no condition to...!
ハァ ハァ ハァ… 幽鬼丸。
Yuukimaru...
ハァ ハァ…。
クソ！
Damn!
草笛…
もしかして 幽鬼丸なのか？
A grass whistle?
Could it be Yuukimaru?!
戻ってこい 幽鬼丸！
Come back! Yuukimaru--!
幽鬼丸！
どこだ？ 幽鬼丸！
Yuukimaru!
Where are you, Yuukimaru?!
クソ！ オレのせいで。
Damn! It's my fault...!
幽鬼丸…。
Yuukimaru...
これは…。
何だって アイツ
こんな大事なもの…。
This is...!
Why would he leave behind something
as important as...?
ヒビひとつ入ってない…。
There isn't even a single crack...
《そうか そういうことか》
I see. So that's it...
(キバ)幽鬼丸が消えた？
まさか あの状態で動けるなんて。
Yuukimaru disappeared?
How could he even move
in his condition?
おい ナルト お前➡
同じ部屋にいたのに
気づかなかったのかよ？
Hey, Naruto.
You were in the room with him.
まあな。
はあ？ なんだよ それ。
Didn't you notice?
No, I guess not.
忍が 聞いて呆れるぜ
さすが下忍！
Huh?! How can you call yourself
a Ninja?!
うっせえな
お前だって寝てたじゃねえかよ！
Just what you'd expect from a Genin!
Shut up!
You were asleep, too, you know!
(キバ)んだと？ オレを スタミナオバケの
テメエと一緒にすんじゃねえ！
Why you...!
(サクラ)アンタたちが もめたって
しかたないでしょ！
Don't put me in the same league
as a stamina freak like you!
Arguing won't do any good!
でも 心配ね 幽鬼丸
行くあてなんかないんだろうし。
But I'm worried about Yuukimaru.
(リー)放ってはおけません！
ここは みんなで捜しましょう！
He has nowhere to go, and...
We can't just ignore him!
Let's all look for him!
そうよね！
(シノ)その必要はない。
I agree!
That won't be necessary.
なぜなら 三尾に関する力を
失った子どもは➡
The reason is...
because a child who lost his power
to control the Three-Tails
我々にとって
もはや脅威ではないからだ。
is no longer a threat to us.
そういう問題ではありません！
いや シノの言うとおりだな。
That's not the issue here!
逃げ出した子どもを わざわざ
捜して出してやる義務はない。
No, Shino is right.
We're under no obligation to look
for a child who ran away.
それに ボクたちには
帰還命令も出ていることだしね。
And besides,
we've been ordered to return.
そんな… いいんですか ナルト君？
But that's...!
ああ 心配ねえ。
Are you okay with that, Naruto?!
アイツなら 大丈夫だってばよ。
Yeah, there's nothing to worry about.
He can handle himself.
ナルト？
Naruto...?
そろそろ出発だな。
お待たせしました カカシさん。
We'd better be on our way.
Sorry to keep you all waiting, Kakashi-san.
(大蛇丸)うまく暁を
揺さぶれればと➡
I was hoping we could have
shaken up the Akatsuki...
思っていたんだけど。
(カブト)申し訳ありません
木ノ葉の邪魔が入るとは
計算外でした。
I'm sorry. I didn't count on
the Leaf Ninja interfering.
それで あの女…
紅蓮は死んだの？
And so, did that woman...
ええ 残念ながら。
Guren die?
なかなか
おもしろい能力の持ち主でしたが。
Regretfully, yes.
She possessed very interesting powers...
フフ 心にもないことを。
Like you mean that...
殺したのは
あなたなんじゃないの？
Maybe you were the one who killed her?
滅相もない。
まあ いいわ。
Heaven forbid.
あの程度の者なら
いくらでも替えがきく。
Well, never mind.
We can find any number of replacements
for someone of her ability.
ですが 幽鬼丸が…。
捨て置きなさい 今となっては…
ゴホッ！
But Yuukimaru...
Leave it.
大蛇丸様！
今 薬をお持ちします！
At this point...
Orochimaru-sama!
ゲホッゲホッ!!
I'll bring your medicine right away!
《もはや あの器も限界か》
That host body has reached its limit...
ハァ ハァ…。
フフフ 今となっては
すべてが無意味。
At this point, it has lost all meaning...
もうすぐ 彼の体が
手に入るのだから。
Because soon,
I will possess his  body...
どうしたの ナルト？
What's the matter, Naruto?
いや なんでもねえ。
No, it's nothing...
フフフ！
定時連絡か？
ああ。
Is that the regular report?
霧が出てきたな。
Yeah...
引継ぎによると
時折 三尾が放出するものらしい。
A fog is forming.
According to the unit we're taking over for,
it's apparently created by
the Three-Tails.
幻覚作用があるから
気をつけろよ。
It induces hallucinations, so be careful.
(デイダラ)ソイツは 初耳だな うん。
That's news to me, hmm...
お前 その装束！
しまっ…。
You! That costume...
Dam--!
フン！
(トビ)いや～ さすがデイダラ先輩！
Humph...
Oh wow! Deidara-senpai,
that was awesome!
見張りはこれで全部ですね。
お前の情報とは
だいぶ違うな うん。
That's the last of the lookouts.
Your info was way off.
確か 木ノ葉と別勢力が
三尾をめぐって➡
"A force separate from
the Leaf Ninja was engaged
派手にぶつかり合ってる。
じゃなかったか？
in a vigorous clash over the Three-Tails."
ん～ そのはずなんですけどね。
おかしいなぁ。
Wasn't that what you said?
Well, that's how it was supposed to be...
That's odd.
まあ でもジャマなのがいなくなって
よかったじゃないですか。
But oh well, it's good that we got rid
of the ones in our way.
今のうちのに とっととノルマ
こなしちゃいましょうよ。
Let's make our quota right now
while we have the chance!
お前が オレに指図するのは
100年早い うん。
You're a hundred years too young
to be giving me orders, hmm...
うん！
ちょ… ちょっと 先輩！ 幻覚の話
聞いてなかったんですか？
H-H-Hey, Senpai!
誰に言ってる？
オイラのアートをなめんなよ。
Weren't you listening to the story
about the hallucinations?
Who do you think you're speaking to?
Don't underestimate my art.
はぁ。 ったく 短気なんだから
Sheesh, he's got a short temper...
ま 三尾を探すったって
結構 広い湖だからな。
That's a huge lake to find
the Three-Tails in.
自分から
出てきてもらうのが早いだろう。
It'd be faster if it appeared on its own.
うん！
いや～ 改めて見るとホント
何か でかい亀みたいですね。
Oh! On closer inspection,
it looks something like a huge turtle.
強そうですね。
A powerful one...
これが三尾か。
やっぱ ここは➡
So that's the Three-Tails...
デイダラ先輩にお任せします。
I think I'll leave it for you to handle,
Deidara-senpai.
トビ！ お前晴れて
暁のメンバーになったんだろ。
Tobi, you formally became
a member of Akatsuki, right?
あとは お前がやれ うん。
You take care of the rest, hmm!
そんな…。
No way...
うわ～っ！
あ～っ！ 来た～っ！
水系のヤツなら
鬼鮫さんに任せたほうが➡
It's coming!
If it's a water creature,
shouldn't we have let Kisame-san handle it?!
よかったんじゃないんですか？
人選ミスでしょ これ！ ギャーッ！
I'd say they assigned
the wrong person for the job!
情けねえな。
Pitiful, I'd say.
喝！
ギャーッ！
Release!
どうかなさいましたか？
いや。
Is something the matter?
No...
皆さん 無事に火の国に
入られたようですね。
It appears everyone has entered
the Land of Fire safely.
そうか ご苦労。
ではカツユ お前は戻れ。
はい。
I see. Good work.
You may now return, Katsuyu.
Yes.
(トビ)やった～！
バンザ～イ！ バンザ～イ！
I did it! Banzai! Banzaai!
デイダラさん！ 見ました オレの術！
コイツ イチコロですよ～！
Deidara-san, did you see my Jutsu?!
Just one time, and bam!
暁のメンバーになって➡
いきなり
こんな大役を任されるのも➡
You can understand why
I was given this important assignment
頷けるってもんでしょ？
オレって やるもんでしょ？
right after formally becoming a member
of Akatsuki, can't you?!
いいや。 オイラの起爆粘土が
アートしただけだろ。
No... It was probably my clay bomb
doing its artistic work.
オイラの芸術のおかげだろうが！
うん。
You have my artistry to thank, hmm.
手を貸してやったのも忘れて➡
１人で盛り上がってんじゃ
ねえよ！
Don't get so carried away that
you forgot that I lent you a hand!
暁のメンバーなら
もっと口数は少なく➡
If you're a member of Akatsuki,
don't talk so much and act more cool.
もっとクールに振る舞え。
要するに➡
クール イコール アートだ！
In other words, "cool = art"!
いいか。 アートってのはな➡
クールな感情から
かもし出される➡
Listen, art is a passionate moment
coming from cool emotions--!
(デイダラ)情熱的な一瞬の…。
(トビ)先輩こそ口数が多いっすね。
ハハハ ハハハ ハハハ…！
Senpai, you talk a lot.
(トビ)ん… 冗談！
(トビ)ギャーッ!!
I was joking...!
どうした？
いや。
湖に向かった連中なんだが➡
What is it?
It's just that...
contact from the unit that headed for
the lake is rather late, don't you think?
連絡が遅くないか？
うん…。
念のため報告をあげておくか。
Let's file a report, just in case.
(デイダラ)いいかトビ。
図に乗ってんじゃねえぞ うん。
Listen, Tobi.
You shouldn't press your luck!
三尾は人柱力じゃなかったぶん
弱かっただけだ。
The Three-Tails was just weak
because it didn't have a Jinchuriki host.
力をコントロールする頭が
なかったからな。
It didn't have a mind to control its power.
はぁ… おいトビ！
そこまでクールに
口数減らすことはねえよ。
Hey, Tobi.
You don't have to be so cool
as to stop talking altogether.
ちゃんと返事くらい…。
(トビ)ムニャ。
At least answer me...
あぁ～ ダメ ダメです。
そ そ そ そこは…。
Hmm?!
Oh that's the spot...
あっ イ イヤ～ン…。
Oh my...
(デイダラ)テメエにゃ
ちょうどいい目覚ましだ！
この野郎!!
This is the perfect wake up
for you, I'd say. You bastard!
(キバ)ふぅ！ 久しぶりに
帰ってきた気がするなぁ！
Wow, it feels like I hadn't
been back in ages.
(シノ)任務につぐ
任務だったからな。
We had one mission after another...
今日の晩メシは
一楽で決まりだぜ！
Dinner tonight is at Ichiraku!
ねぇ ナルト！
Say, Naruto.
ん？
幽鬼丸のことだけど➡
Huh?
ホントに あれでよかったわけ？
About Yuukimaru...
Are you sure it was best that way?
アンタ あんなに気にしてたのに。
You used to worry so much about him.
いいんだ！
どうせ捜したって➡
That's okay.
簡単には
見つかんなかったろうし。
Besides, even if we went looking for him,
he wouldn't be easy to find anyway.
どういうこと？
やっぱさ➡
What do you mean?
エロ仙人の言葉は正しかったんだ。
The Pervy Sage's words
were true, after all.
思ってるヤツがいるところが
帰る場所なんだって。
He said wherever someone cares
about you is the place you return to.
思って思って思い続ければ➡
If you believe, and keep thinking,
about that person...
それは絶対
通じるんだってばよ！
your feelings will surely get across, he said.
えっ これって… まさか!?
What? Is this... what I think it is?
だから オレらも思い続けようぜ。
So... we should keep thinking, too.
サスケの帰る場所。
作っとかなきゃなんねえしな。
We need to create a place
that Sasuke can return to.
うん！
Right.
before the reality of a deep breath
sonzai to shinkokyuu no genjitsu wo mae ni
my gaze my very existence tries to challenge it
idomou to suru shisen wa
mistakes are made and in the confusion of it all everything burns into my mind
machigai mo tomadoi mo zenbu yaki tsukeru
in a series of moments
isshun no renzoku no naka de
beyond a great number of promises
ikutsu mono yakusoku no sono ue ni tatte wa
are the words that spilled over from the day as I reflect upon them
kamishimeru ano hi koboreochita kotoba
it's as though I made a vow which expresses these feelings into words
komerareta omoi wa chikai no you de
then it would link the befinning with the present day
kuchi ni sureba ima to hajimari wo tsunagu
it's not in my dreams
yume de wa nakute
that place doesn't exist in a fantasy world either
esoragoto no sekai de mo nai basho de sa
before the reality of a deep breath
sonzai to shinkokyuu no genjitsu no mae ni
my gaze my very existence tries to challenge it
idomou to suru shisen wa
mistakes are made and in the confusion of it all everything burns into my mind
machigai mo tomadoi mo zenbu yaki tsukete
embracing the long path ahead
sono zutto saki wo toraeru
in a series of moments
isshun no renzoku no naka de
Next Episode
So that's your move...
Just as I expected.
You are weaker than me...
There's no longer any need for me
to give you my body.
You Uchiha fledgling...!
If I hadn't been a fledgling,
you'd have had no chance at me, right?
Silence!
I don't like the way you do things.
You continue to toy with others
for your own pathetic reasons...
You make me sick!
Next time: "The Serpent's Pupil"
The Serpent's Pupil